

Full-stack web developer and web designer with a background in communications and graphic design. Specializing in the MERN and MEAN tech stacks to create responsive and aesthetically pleasing web applications, while implementing self-driven solutions and dynamic creativity.

## **EDUCATION**

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development

Career Foundry: Full Stack Immersion Graduated 2021

Certificate in Graphic Design Red Rocks Community College Graduated 2017

Bachelors of Arts in Communication Colorado Christian University Graduated 2016



https://github.com/JBorchers

linkedin.com/in/jordan-borchers

Denver, Colorado

jordanborchers@gmail.com

720.841.6259

### **SKILLS**



# SAMPLE WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

### MYFLIX | Angular | September 2021

A single-page, responsive movie application built using the **MEAN stack** (MongoDB, Express, Angular, and Node.js). This app allows registered users to browse movies by specific criteria and update personal information, including a list of favorite movies.

**Live project:** <a href="https://jborchers.github.io/myFlix-Angular-client/">https://jborchers.github.io/myFlix-Angular-client/</a>

### MEET APP | React Native | June 2021

A RESTful API created using Node.js and Express, which interacts with MongoDB (a non-relational database). The API can be accessed using HTTP methods like GET, POST, PUSH, and DELETE. I used CRUD (create, read, update, delete) methods to interact with the data stored in the database.

GitHub: https://github.com/JBorchers/movie\_api

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **MISSIONS DOOR, Denver**

Communications Coordinator | May 2019 - Present

- Responsible for all **website management** using WordPress and Elementor
- Creation and maintaining of web pages and campaigns for the website
- Coordinate the **design** and distribution of communication material and resources for all personnel in the organization, such as brochures, flyers, business cards, and video using Adobe Creative Suite
- Develop the creative writing and visual design of monthly newsletters

Admin Assistant & Personnel Coordinator | December 2017 - May 2019

- Data visualization for financial reports using Adobe Creative Suit and interactive presentations with Microsoft Excel to develop easy-to-understand reports for the Board, Executive Leadership, Office Staff, and donor base
- Coordinating candidate applications and background checks, working to guide local and international applicants through onboarding process
- **Event coordinating**, overseeing several regional events, budgeting, communicating with venues and catering companies, and attendee support

#### AMERICAN MOUNTAINEERING MUSEUM, Golden

Marketing & Social Media Intern | March 2017 – January 2018

- Management of **social media marketing** to promote museum and events
- Assist in set-up and running of promotional events, volunteer coordinating
- Designing of logos and digital/print advertisements using Adobe programs

#### **FREELANCE DESIGN**

Graphic Designer | 2014 - Present

 Commissioned for graphic design of custom logo designs, flyers, and marketing material for a multitude of startup businesses and nonprofits, such as The Colorado Mountain Club and Paladin Rescue